Independent component analysis is
独立成分分析是
a method similar to PCA and random projection
同主成分分析和随机投影相似的方法
in that it takes a set of features and
它同样会选取一些特征
produces a different set that is useful in some way.
产生另外一个有一定作用的集
But it's different in that while PCA works to maximize variance,
但不同之处是 主成分分析用于最大化方差
ICA assumes that the features are mixtures of
独立成分分析假定这些特征是独立源的混合
independent sources and it tries to isolate
并尝试分离这些
these independent sources that are sort of mixed in this dataset.
混合在该数据集里的独立源
The classic example used to explain ICA is something called the cocktail party problem.
用于解释独立成分分析的典型例子是鸡尾酒会问题
Let's look at a variation of this problem.
我们来看该问题的一个变形
So let's say that three of your friends go to an art show and there are three curtains.
假定你的三个朋友参加一场艺术展 这里有三个帘子
One of them opens up and there's a person playing
其中一个打开了 里面有一人在弹钢琴
a piano and they play a nice tune on the piano.
且曲调优美
You weren't there to listen to it so you assume that it sounded good.
你当时没在现场听 你假设它很好听
And then after a little bit of time
过了一会儿
another curtain is uncovered and there's a person playing the cello.
另一个帘子打开 里边有一人在拉大提琴
And the piano is still playing and then cello starts playing but
钢琴仍在弹奏 大提琴也在演奏
they're playing two different pieces that don't really work together.
这是两种不同的声音 在一起不太和谐
So there's sort of mixing together.
这就是某种混合
And then the third curtain is opened and then there's a TV turned on
然后 第三个帘子打开 里边有一台打开的电视机
and there's just this sign wave noise coming and it's a little bit of a mess.
它传出的只有信号波动噪声 听起来有些混乱
And so here your friends decide that,
此时 你的朋友觉得
okay, this is kind of interesting.
这有些有趣
Let's take our phones out and record this.
决定拿出手机 将声音录下来
So they record let's say six seconds of audio for this and so each person,
所以他们录音了 我们假设每人录了 6 秒钟的音频
this friend was closer to the piano so they have more piano and they're recording.
这个朋友更靠近钢琴 所以录音里钢琴声更明显
This person was closer to the TV so they have more TV.
这个朋友更靠近电视 所以电视声音更明显
And so you have these three recordings.
你现在有这三份录音
And then each of them has a different level of the original source which you don't have.
每份录音含有不同程度的原始来源 而你没有原始来源
You don't have these recordings.
你没有进行录音
So the first one sounds kind of like this
所以 第一份听起来就像这样
where the TV noise is a little faint and you can hear the piano and the cello.
电视噪音有些弱 你可以听到钢琴声和大提琴声
The second one, there's a little bit more cello and the TV got louder.
第二份录音里 大提琴声音有些增强 电视变得更响
And the third one we can even see it here that the TV is the loudest.
第三份录音里 我们甚至可以看出来电视声音最大
So if you have only these three recordings,
所以 如果你只有这三份录音
is there a way for you to retrieve the original signals datasets?
你可不可以溯回到原始信号或数据集呢？
And the answer is yes.
答案是 可以
That's what an example of what independent component analysis allows you to do.
这就是可以运用独立成分分析的一个例子
And so ICA takes these three samples or this dataset
独立成分分析采用这三个样本
of three dimensions and
或这个三维的数据集
we tell it there are three original components that were in there,
这里有三个原组分
so can you find them in here?
你能在这里找到吗？
So it would output piano.
这里输出的是钢琴的声音
So when it's able to work it is able to isolate them.
它起作用时可以将它们分离
And then the second output would be the cello and then the TV would be the last one.
那第二个输出的为大提琴的声音 最后一个为电视的声音
And so this is a type of problem called the blind
这是一种由独立成分分析解决的
source separation and that's the problem that ICA solves.
叫做盲源分离的问题